

APPLIED SCIENTIST II | SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

、 (+91) 9495735801 | ♥ Kochi, Kerala, India | @ varma.nsreedevi@gmail.com | ♥ sree-varma | in sreedevi-varma-n

Summary .

Data Scientist with more than 1 year of experience in banking sector. I have owned and managed multiple products during this period including multiple end-to-end model deployments. I am also a Physics PhD graduate with inter-disciplinary academic research experience in Deep Learning, Particle Physics and Cosmology. I have a background in data generation and preprocessing coupled with strong experience in building, training and evaluation of deep learning models like DNNs, CNNs and RNNs. I am a machine learning enthusiast with keen interest in development of models to tackle real world business problems.

Skills_____

Programming Language proficiency

Python

Libraries used

Tensorflow 2.0, Tensorflow 1.14, Keras, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Multiprocessing, Pandas, Joblib, Numpy, Scipy, Amplitude, Metabase, Spinnaker

Models Built

CNN, LSTM, REGRESSION and RASA conversational model

Experience __

Applied Scientist II

Bangalore/Remote, IN

JUPITER MONEY

January 2023- Present

- Managing the science side of the project
- Currently working on the science side of creating a *Conversational Search* tab for the customers, which has a huge impact on customer experience

Applied Scientist I Bangalore/Remote, IN

JUPITER MONEY

October 2021- December 2022

- Explored multiple data sources and did extensive analysis for finding the affinity towards different financial institutions.
- Conducted research and built algorithms/models for the business problems of interest.
- Owned/Contributed to the following projects:
 - Normalisation of raw merchant names in the transactional data, which impacted the user experience
 - End-to-end management on the data science front of the FAQ pipeline, a biweekly iteration which included all the information of the product.
 - Conversational bot to fetch appropriate FAQs to the customer.
 - Insights from transactional SMS of the customers to create new products/features.
 - End-to-end management of a conversational bot with intents like, greet, FAQ, gibberish, out-of-scope, and human-handoff.
 - Currently working on the science side of creating a *Conversational Search* tab for the customers, which has a huge impact on customer experience

PhD Researcher London, UK

KING'S COLLEGE LONDON

October 2016- July 2021

- Generated and preprocessed Particle Physics and Cosmological data. Parallelised the data generation process to make it more efficient using python libraries.
- Built and implemented various Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) architectures in studying the underlying physics from the simulated data.
- Trained and evaluated the machine learning models using Tensorflow and Keras. Fine-tuned the models by optimizing various hyperparameters.
- Published results in internationally renowned journals and presented my work at various international physics conferences to world leading
 experts in the field.

Education _____

PhD in Physics

King's College London

London, UK

October 2016 - July 2021

• Deep Learning Applications to Jet Tagging and Subhalo hunts.

National Institute of Technology Karnataka (NITK)

MASTER OF SCIENCE (MSc) IN PHYSICS

• GPA: 8.59/10

Maharaja's College Ernakulam, Mahathma Gandhi University

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BSc) IN PHYSICS

- Mathematics and Statistics as complementary.
- GPA: 3.62/4

Ernakulam, Kerala, India

Surathkal, Karnataka, India

July 2011 - May 2014

July 2014 - June 2016

Publications

Deep Learning Applications to Jet Tagging and Subhalo hunts.

SREEDEVI VARMA

2021

PhD Thesis

2020

Sensing Higgs boson cascade decays through memory.

CHRISTOPH ENGLERT, MALCOLM FAIRBAIRN, MICHAEL SPANNOWSKY, PANAGIOTIS STYLIANOU, AND SREEDEVI VARMA

Phys. Rev. D 102, 095027

Dark Matter Subhalos, Strong Lensing and Machine Learning.

SREEDEVI VARMA, MALCOLM FAIRBAIRN, AND JULIO FIGUEROA

arXiv 2005.05353 2020

The Machine Learning Landscape of Top Taggers.

Anja Butter et al.

SciPost Phys., 7:014

2019

Reports of My Demise Are Greatly Exaggerated:N-subjettiness Taggers Take On Jet

LIAM MOORE, KARL NORDSTRÖM, SREEDEVI VARMA AND MALCOLM FAIRBAIRN

SciPost Phys., 7(3):036

Projects.

Dark Matter signal search.

CONFERENCE KAGGLE COMPETITION

• Built a classifier to identify dark matter signal.

Kaggle

2019

July 2017

Alcubierre's Drive: A study using ADM formalism and Energy Conditions

MASTER'S THESIS

• Study on warp drive or hyper-fast travel within the framework of General Relativity.

National Institute of Technology Karnataka (NITK)

July 2015 – May 2016

Simulating Random walk using Python

MINI-PROJECT

• Simulation of Random walk and its application to problems like Browninan motion.

National Institute of Technology Karnataka (NITK)

December 2015 - May 2016

A Pseudo-Newtonian approach to Bondi accretion flow across static black holes

SUMMER INTERNSHIP

• Study of Bondi flow in to a static blackhole.

Indian Institute of Science (IISc)

May 2015 - July 2015

A Study on Comet ISON's Orbit

Undergraduate Thesis

• Study on position of the Comet ISON or C/2012 S1.

Maharaja's Collge Ernakulam

June 2013 – December 2013

Conferences _____

Sept 2019	PALS 2019, Speaker: Paris-Amsterdam-London-Stockholm 9th meeting	LPTHE, Paris
Jan 2019	YETI 2019, Speaker: Young Experimentalists & Theorists Institute Conference	IPPP, Durham
July 2018	BOOST 2018, 10th International Workshop on Boosted Object Phenomenology, Reconstruction and Searches in HEP	LPTHE, Paris
July 2019	IML 2018, Speaker: Machine Learning Workshop	CERN, Geneva
Sept 201	$7~\Lambda$ CDM and Beyond, Cosmology Tools in Theory and in Practice	Corfu, Greece
Aug 2017	BUSSTEPP, British Universities Summer School in Theoretical Elementary Particle Physics	London, UK
July 2017	MLHEP, Machine Learning for High Energy Physics	Reading, UK
Jan 2017	YETI/ YTF, Young Experimentalists & Theorists Institute Conference	IPPP, Durham